Episode 12
The Starry Bridge that Leads to the Night Sky
Eh?!
I'm playing the role of the Ogami in the festival?
How did that happen?
You didn't know?
The winner of the Hikonan Race is assigned the role of the Ogami for that year.
Didn't I tell you?
I never heard anything like that.
Anyway, didn't Koyori win the race?
No matter how much of a tomboy Koyori-chan is, she's still a girl.
She obviously isn't suitable for the role of the Ogami, right?
Well, I suppose so.
You're the runner-up, Kazuma-kun, so you're going to do it.
Fate has chosen you as our participant, so please do your best.
Okay...
But is it really okay?
A person like me, from the big city, playing such an important role?
What are you talking about?
We're more than happy to have you for this, actually!
Although this festival is for celebrating the legend of the Twin Mountains,
to be the helper of the gods, or basically, taking in other people from other towns,
is considered a divine blessing.
That's why we're hoping people like you, Kazuma-kun,
will come to our town to play the Ogami role
and create a fresh new batch of descendants.
What are you talking about so early in the morning?!
Onii-chan, what does "descendants" mean?
Well, that's...
Ayumu-kun, a descendant is-
Nee-san!
Must be nice, playing the role of the Ogami.
You really think so?
Hey, the Megami is played by Tsumugi-san, you know.
That poyoyon poyoyon tapun tapun...!
That's all you think about, huh?
Hey Bro, how about you take this chance and confess your love?
Why do I have to do that?!
Didn't you know?
In the past, the Ogami was allowed to confess to the Megami during the calling-out ceremony.
Eh?
I see.
Tsumugi-san is great, but normally the one chosen for the role of Megami is the most beautiful girl in town.
Of course, there are guys who would want to make their move on her,
and in fact, the Hikonan Race was originally
founded as a way to fight for the right to confess.
Really?
A few generations ago, there were quite a few cases where the Megami and the Ogami ended up together because of this.
There's even a rumour that those who have confessed their love...
...and become a couple because of the race will bring about a good harvest year.
But why do I have to confess to Tsumugi-san?
Good morning!
What are you two discussing so early in the morning?
What's up with Tsumugi-san?
Ah, it's nothing...
Good morning!
Ah... good morning.
Geez, my mum talks so much. She never stops!
Bro, you have anything planned today?
Shall we all go to Backpipe?
I'll pass.
I've got club activities.
Me too.
I have to attend a meeting at the shrine.
So that means Ui, too?
Y-Yup, that's right.
Tch. Can't be helped.
I'll just go grab a bite and head home then.
If you're feeling lonely, I'll accompany you.
Since the festival is coming up, you must be in a festive mood.
I'll quench that thirst for fun you've got!
We shall have a face-to-face talk with each other!
Well, it sure was a surprise to hear
that I was going to play the Ogami.
I guess so.
I would've been surprised, too.
Um...
Erm...
What is it?
Well, you see...
You first.
It's nothing.
There's no conversation.
When did you show up?
At least tell us you're there!
What's wrong?
If we don't hurry, we'll be late.
Wow!
Amazing! It suits you, Onii-san!
You look really handsome.
Thank you...
Then, I'll be taking a shot!
Eh?
Kasane-chan, I don't mind the photos, but why are you here?
I'm collecting data!
As the "Fast Eared Girl" of Yamabiko Town,
I can't just pass up such juicy information!
Ah, for your information,
I'm not taking Mugi-nee's photo to sell to the Koutobu brothers.
I'm totally not doing that.
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
Wow!
Mugi-nee, you're beautiful!
Thank you, Kasane-chan.
Hina-senpai and Nakatsugawa-senpai both
look like shrine maidens. They're great, too!
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
The tea is here.
Sorry to have you help us, when you're a guest.
It's nothing.
You weren't used to that outfit, so you must be tired.
Ah, not really.
Where's Nakatsugawa-senpai?
She's in the washroom.
She said that since she had to stay in full dress, she was holding it all this time.
My, she should have just said so.
Excuse me, I need to go to the washroom, too.
That reminds me, Koumoto-senpai is playing the role of the Angel this year, right?
Yes. That's why I've been busy practising every day.
Won't you model your outfit for us?
I could, but it doesn't have to be now...
I want to see Senpai wearing that outfit!
I know!
Since we're at it, do you mind striking a
pose and letting me take a photo of you?
Isn't that good?
You'll have to show yourself in that outfit anyway.
Then it's decided!
After we finish eating our bean jelly, let's go and get you changed!
Eh?!
Ui-chan.
Tsumugi-san..
Could I talk to you for a bit?
Ui-chan, did you have a fight with Kazuma-san?
Then, why?
I noticed that something is different between you and Kazuma-san.
That's...
I'm sorry.
If you don't want to tell me, I won't force-
I realised.
Eh?
I've been thinking about Kazu-kun being
like a brother to me, and because of that,
when I'm with him, I always have fun, and I get soft, warm feelings of happiness.
But...
But, my brother is my brother, and I realised that Kazu-kun isn't him.
And then, I couldn't find a way to speak normally to Kazu-kun.
When our eyes make contact, my chest tightens suddenly,
and when I'm alone at home, all I think about is Kazu-kun and my cheeks get all hot...
Ui-chan, that's love.
No!
That's not true!
That's not true...
It's just that my heart races when I think about Kazu-kun.
It's not l-love or anything!
It's... It's totally different. I mean...
Ui and Tsumugi-san are really taking a while.
I wonder what happened.
Hoshino.
Why didn't you tell Ui that she was cute?
Where did that question come from?!
Hoshino, you thought Ui was cute when you looked at her,
but you didn't say it.
Why?
"Why?" you ask...
That time when I left my house and my dad came to bring me back,
Hoshino, you helped me say what I wanted to say.
Back then, I was really happy.
But after that, I realised that I had to say what I wanted to say on my own.
I had always wanted to apologise for
misunderstanding and getting angry at you.
That's why I was really happy when I finally managed to apologise to you properly.
Hoshino, if you have something you want to say, you should speak up about it.
Senpai.
Ui-chan, that's love.
Love, huh?
That's...
I don't even know, myself.
Love...
I don't even know what it is.
That's the third time you've yawned this morning.
What happened?
I was up late last night.
Are you all right?
Don't you have to practise for the festival after school?
Yup.
I'll sleep during lunch break. I'll be fine.
Well then, I'll make a brief run-through of the festival procedure.
I'll be more detailed about the difficult parts during the practice sessions,
so please try to get a general idea of the procedures.
First, Madoka will be playing the Angel and will arrive in the human realm.
After that, the Ogami, waiting at the bottom of the steps, will receive the scroll from the Angel.
Next, the Ogami will descend the flight of stone steps, and ride the carriage waiting at the bottom.
The Megami will change into the ceremonial clothes and stand by with the two Arks.
Tsumugi-chan has experience with the Ark role, so this part should be fine for you, right?
Yes.
After the Ogami's carriage has started moving, we will contact you, and at the arranged time,
the Megami and the Arks will set off.
When you reach the bridge, they will start playing the taiko,
which signals the start of the calling-out ceremony.
The Ogami will read the scroll he received from the Angel,
while the Megami will read the scroll she received from the Arks.
Every year, the scrolls are written by the Angel, aren't they?
Yes.
Using dew collected on the morning of the festival, I make ink and write the scrolls.
So, Koumoto-senpai can write those squiggly words!
Erm, one question...
What is it, Kazuma-kun?
"Those squiggly words" refers to the words on the scrolls, right?
I can't read any of those words at all.
It'll be fine.
For both scrolls, the furigana for the words will be written on the remaining space in the scrolls.
Oh, I see...
Are you relieved?
Yes.
If all I have to do is read what's written.
That's why you have to keep your cool.
Even though you're just reading from the scroll,
if you bring out your feelings while saying those words,
it will become a statement of truth to the Megami.
If you bring out your feelings while saying those words, it will become a statement of truth.
Ah!
So here, I shake it twice, spin around, and after that-
Hmm?
Hello-
Hello?
Tsumugi-senpai?
Eh?
You want to pretend that you're sick?
Hoshizora e Kakaru Hashi
Yamabiko Community Centre
Sign: Megami Resting Room
It's about time. They said that you should go and change.
Ah, okay!
Then...
Mugi-nee, what's wrong?
My stomach...
My stomach suddenly...
Eh?!
Ah, we need a doctor...
No, call an ambulance!
I'm fine, Ui-chan.
If I rest, it should go away.
But...
More importantly, the Megami role...
It's impossible, Mugi-nee.
It would be better to ask for a replacement.
Ui-chan, could you do it for me?
Eh?!
I can't do it!
Asking me to be the Megami out of the blue...
Ui-chan, since you've been practising with me for so long, you should know the procedure, right?
Just do it as you're supposed to.
That's why, please...
But, if I do that, then we'll be one Ark short...
That's fine.
There's a replacement Ark here.
Eh?!
Me?!
Impossible, impossible, impossible!
Kasane has been taking photos of us practising for quite a while.
You should be familiar with the procedure, too.
I guess so.
It's an emergency!
"Do it", or "Please do it": Take your pick!
Please let me do it!
Onii-chan, concentrate!
I love you, Ui
Even though you're just reading from the scroll,
if you bring out your feelings while saying those words,
it will become a statement of truth to the Megami.
Hoshino, if you have something you want to say, you should speak up about it.
I love you, Ui
Although it might not have been from the moment we met, when I realised it,
when I was with you, well...
Anyway, I love you
Ui!
What's your reply?
I.. I...
I can't hear you!
Say it louder!
I... Kazu-kun... too...
Louder, Ui!
I love Kazu-kun, too!
I love you. I love you. I really love you!
futari de mita haruka kanata no ryuusei
The distant shooting star we saw.
haato no puromisu
Believe in our promise. As much as you'd call it true love.
ai to ieru hodo shinjite
You stop, as if you'd do that...
Don't be shy, we've got lots of sake and food, so please speak up if you want more!
Sorry to bother you.
A bunch of guys who can drink to their heart's content here.
What are you saying?
kaze ni yureru kami osaeru you ni
...to keep your hair from fluttering in the wind.
Letting me serve you sake to fill you up on the day of the festival is my pleasure.
kimi wa tomadoi
I painted my cheeks red...
koi no hajimari to kidukanai de hoo wo akakushita
...so I wouldn't notice that I had fallen in love.
But!
I won't forgive you if you drink too much and ruin the place.
ikusen no hikari ryoute de hora
You have myriads of light rays in your hand.
hoshi wo sukutte
Come on and save that star.
hitori no yoru demo waraeru you ni
So you can smile even on a night when you're alone.
omoi de wo hanabi ni shite
Turn them into fireworks of your memories.
But, to think we would see another confession during the calling-out ceremony...
kimi to boku no uta ni nare
And let them become a song for us.
It reminds me of what you did back then.
saa ten made todoke kono kimochi
Let the heavens know...
Sadly, you were rejected, right?
kokoro wo gyutto tsunagou
...about our love that connects us firmly.
Gen-san, that's a personal matter.
yowakutatte iin da boku no te de
It's okay if you're weak.
sono yume wo hippatte iku
I'll grab your hand and realise your dream.
Another glass!
kakehashi ni na itai yo
I want to become your only bridge.
Erm, dear Mother, it seems like you've had quite a bit to drink. Any more would be...
kimi hitori no kirari niji ni naru deshou
I'm sure we will be shining forever...
Huh?!
You got something to say to your mother?!
boku ni kimi wo eien ni
...brightly like a rainbow.
I only drink so much in the first place
because you cause me so much trouble!
Do you get it?
Understood!
Most probably both of us...
tabun bokutachi wa
...are searching for a better tomorrow with our bare hands.
tesaguri shite ashita wo motome
Well then, fill 'er up!
Yes!
The times we get angry and the times we feel sad,
toki ni okottari naitari shite
Eh?
Ayumu, you're an artist!
become the scars in our heart.
kizuna ni kaeru yo
Could I have you draw one of me next time?
Although our future isn't written in the horoscopes.
Horoscope ni wa mirai chizu wa kaitenai kedo
Even though I look like this, when I'm nude, I'm actually pretty great.
We both pointed at the vast sky.
futari yubisashita oozora ni wa
Eh?
It's the start of a story.
monogatari no hajimari ga
The birth of it can be heard already.
ubugoe wo ageru deshou
What's up with that thing, Koyo-nee?
Come on, let's fly up the shining hill.
saa kagayaku oka de tobitatou
It's nice, isn't it?
Come along with me.
boku ni tsuiteoide
I got it while playing ring toss at the festival!
Even if you cry, I will protect you with these wings of mine.
tatoe namida shite mo kono tsubasa nurasanu you ni tsutsumu kara
That's quite cute-
Ah!
"I will always walk the same path as you."
「onnaji michi wo zutto aruite yukou」
Don't touch that part!
I'm sorry, but I don't want you to find me.
gomen mitsukaranain da
This is very delicious!
To say anything beyond this...
kore ijou no kotoba nante...
Mugi-nee, didn't you have a stomach ache?
My, did I?
We were rejected.
That's right.
I wasn't really rejected or anything.
Hmm?
Well, whatever.
Wow!
We saw it, huh?
The bridge that leads to the starry sky.
It's beautiful.
That's right.
You are very beautiful.